From Gemstate Chronicle
published April 1st 2026 Release
Idaho aims to anchor new nuclear
innovation campus in Idaho
Gemstate Chronicle Gemstate
Chronicle release Idaho aims to
anchor new nuclear innovation
campus in Idaho for immediate
release March 31st 2026 Boise
Idaho Governor Brad Little
announced today the state of
Idaho has submitted its response
to the U S Department of
Energy's DOE Request for
Information inviting states to
express interest in hosting
nuclear lifecycle innovation
campuses a new federal effort to
modernize the nation's full
nuclear fuel cycle and
strengthen America's leadership
in advanced nuclear energy This
initiative would further
solidify Idaho's position as the
nation's leader in nuclear
innovation Idaho is prepared to
continue our tradition of
nuclear excellence and build on
the foundation that has already
made our state great Nuclear
power presents an opportunity
for Idaho families to continue
receiving affordable clean
energy far into the future and I
support the growth of Idaho's
nuclear industry I hope the
Department of Energy will
recognize Idaho's historic
nuclear leadership and its
strong candidacy for this
initiative Governor Little said
States selected to host a
nuclear lifecycle innovation
campus would serve as central
hubs for advanced nuclear
development Securing this
designation would bolster
Idaho's economy expand access to
reliable baseload power and
position the state at the
forefront of next generation
nuclear technologies Idaho's
response was prepared in
coordination with the newly
established Advanced Nuclear
Energy Task Force created by
executive order in September
2025 The submission is supported
by more than a dozen letters
from private industry as well as
federal state and local leaders
underscoring broad momentum
behind Idaho's proposal During a
time of rising energy demand
there is no better place than
Idaho to find new solutions for
power generation Idaho's long
history of partnering with the
Idaho National Lab has prepared
the state for success in the new
nuclear renaissance Idaho is
home to the world's first power
generating nuclear reactor and
is a world class partner for the
U S Department of Energy to
continue doing business with
said Callie Younger OEMR
administrator and Advanced
Nuclear Energy Task Force member
Idaho's response can be viewed
at three one more characters
truncated